{
    "id": "Politica_82",
    "claim": "In the midst of a bloody battle between PP and Ciudadanos over the political space of the center right, these two formations have chosen to shield their pact of government in Andalusia with an extension of the agreement signed two years ago that guarantees stability until the end of the legislature. This is an addition of five points that add to that pact, endorsed this Tuesday by the Governing Council, and which stands out above all for including a kind of 'Pact Anti-Transfuguism bis' with which they undertake not to remove elected positions, after the national leadership of the PP has failed to comply with the original Anti-Transfuguism Pact, which it signed in Congress, by promoting and accepting three Cs fugitives to thwart the motion of censure in Murcia and to preserve the regional government. The initiative, cooked during the weekend while PP and Cs were shooting to death on social networks, has left the team of President Juan Manuel Moreno Bonilla to his government partners, according to sources of Presidency. The first clause of this addendum is precisely the commitment to exhaust the mandate, until the elections are formally held, at the end of 2022. 'In Spain there is political instability, not in Andalusia ', has sentenced the vice president of the Board and regional leader of Cs, Juan Marín. The other most important clause is the commitment that neither PP nor Cs 'shall favour or accept any transfer of public representatives or elected from one party to another of the Government ', i.e. that they shall not admit the escape of leaders of Cs to the PP, as has happened in Murcia, nor vice versa. Point two of this addendum reads as follows: 'Respect for the autonomy of the two parties that make up the Andalusian Government, with the commitment that there should be no movement between political formations with parliamentary representation'. This clause against transfuguism implies that the Andalusian PP and President Moreno Bonilla depart from the national strategy of their party, whose general secretary, Teodoro García Egea, has appealed to the public representatives and elected citizens to leave their party and 'return to the PP house'. The orange formation fit this message as an 'assault ', 'a hostile, gruesome and disrespectful takeover'. The Andalusian president has understood that Pablo Casado's strategy to swallow Ciudadanos, after the political earthquake in Murcia and Madrid, can destabilize his Executive, the most'solid'center right coalition of all those signed by PP and Cs in Spain, and the first alternative of government in Andalusia, after 37 years of the PSOE in power. 'We have spent four decades complaining that the PP did not have other parties with which to agree in Andalusia and now that there is one, that has helped us to break down the socialists, will we charge it? ', insist sources close to Moreno, aware that 'today, Cs and Vox reach an Andalusian electorate that is not yet within the reach of the PP'. This new 'stability agreement 'has been presented after the Governing Council by Marin and the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo, the two most visible sides of the coalition. Both have stressed that the legislature pact signed two years ago is '90 per cent fulfilled ', and that the expansion announced on Tuesday comes to 'strengthen 'the commitments and 'ensure the stability of the Andalusian Executive until the elections, which take place at the end of 2022 '.'We have signed that in this legislature, everyone stays where they are. Let's finish it where we start, and then we'll see ', Bendodo has summed up, not mentioning at any time the word'transfugal '[in fact, it doesn't appear in the signed document]. The spokesman of the Board is the one who has transferred the agreement with Citizens to the secretary general of the PP, and has explained that the PP 'has understood and supports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government, so that there is no interference or external noise '. Bendodo has tried to explain that 'it is not incompatible 'the call of García Egea for the public offices of Cs to pass to the PP with the new pact anti-transfuguism of Andalusia. 'I agree with the national leadership of the party, the PP is an open door party to enter and leave ', he insisted. But the joint appearance of Marin and Bendodo has immediately revealed the different views on the political crisis facing their parties. Why this agreement if you have already signed the Anti-Tranfuguism Pact, which affects the same commitment? 'An Anti-Transfuguism Pact was agreed and signed by the two of us, and now there is an agreement between PP and Cs in Andalusia to ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time ', Marín stressed. Asked if the PP's national leadership had failed to comply with the Anti-Transfuguism Pact, signed a few months ago in Congress, Bendodo has answered emphatically that no; and Marín has replied that'in Andalusia no, but in Murcia I am clear that yes'.'For me those three Cs counselors are fugitives ', he has riveted. The other three points of the stability guarantee agreement deepen the Government's commitments that have already been developed: 'Shielding of health, education and social policies '; 'Economic drive and compliance with the road map for economic reactivation, for which priority is given to the implementation of a second Support Plan for the sectors affected by the health and economic crisis, which will be adopted imminently '; 'Deepening democratic regeneration and reform policy, after decades of mismanagement and corruption of socialist governments in Andalusia'. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.eldiario.es",
    "date": "17/03/2021",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "Board between PP and Ciudadanos over the political space Marin and the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo, the two most visible sides of the coalition with an extension of the agreement signed two years ago that guarantees stability until the end of the legislature .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who are the two most visible sides of the coalition?",
                    "answer": "PP and Ciudadanos"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the agreement signed two years ago that guarantees stability until the end of the legislature?",
                    "score": 0.6012,
                    "answers": "over the political space Marin and the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo|prep\tthe political space Marin and the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo|pobj\tMarin and the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the agreement between PP and Ciudadanos?",
                    "score": 0.5678,
                    "answers": "the legislature|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the two most visible sides of the coalition?",
                    "score": 0.5279,
                    "answers": "the two most visible sides of the coalition|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "the Andalusian PP and President Moreno Bonilla add to that pact, endorsed this Tuesday the Andalusian PP and President Moreno Bonilla the Governing Council, and which stands out above all for including a the public representatives and elected citizens PP and Ciudadanos everyone their party to remove elected 's , after the national leadership of PP the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo to comply with the original Anti-Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla by promoting and accepting Pablo Casado's the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo their party of censure in Murcia and Board government.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What kind of citizens did the PP and Ciudadanos have to remove?",
                    "answer": "elected"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the original Anti-transfuguism?",
                    "score": 0.7667,
                    "answers": "for including a the public representatives and elected citizens PP and Ciudadanos everyone their party to remove elected 's , after the national leadership of PP the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo to comply with the original Anti - Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla by promoting and accepting Pablo Casado 's the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo their party of censure in Murcia and Board government|prep\tincluding a the public representatives and elected citizens PP and Ciudadanos everyone their party to remove elected 's , after the national leadership of PP the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo to comply with the original Anti - Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla by promoting and accepting Pablo Casado 's the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo their party of censure in Murcia and Board government|pcomp\tafter the national leadership of PP the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo to comply with the original Anti - Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla by promoting and accepting Pablo Casado 's the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo their party of censure in Murcia and Board government|prep\tto comply with the original Anti - Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla by promoting and accepting Pablo Casado 's the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo their party of censure in Murcia and Board government|advcl\twith the original Anti - Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla|prep\tthe original Anti - Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the Andalusian PP and President Moreno Bonilla do to comply with the original Anti-transfuguism?",
                    "score": 0.7333,
                    "answers": "which stands out above all for including a the public representatives and elected citizens PP and Ciudadanos everyone their party to remove elected 's , after the national leadership of PP the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo to comply with the original Anti - Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla by promoting and accepting Pablo Casado 's the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo their party of censure in Murcia and Board government|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the original Anti-transfuguism?",
                    "score": 0.7213,
                    "answers": "the national leadership of PP the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo to comply with the original Anti - Transfuguism the word'transfugal ' President Moreno Bonilla by promoting and accepting Pablo Casado 's the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo their party of censure in Murcia and Board government|pobj\tthe word'transfugal ' President|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of censure in Murcia and Board government?",
                    "score": 0.6646,
                    "answers": "of censure in Murcia and|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The initiative, This new 'stability agreement ' during the weekend while This new 'stability agreement ' PP and Ciudadanos were shooting to death on PP networks, has left the team of President Juan Manuel Moreno Bonilla Andalusia to government partners, according We sources the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo .",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Bendodo say about the agreement?",
                    "score": 0.6295,
                    "answers": "according We sources the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo|prep\tWe sources the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo|pobj\tthe Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the new agreement between PP and Ciudadanos?",
                    "score": 0.6063,
                    "answers": "on 17/03/2021|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship agreement between President Juan Manuel Moreno Bonilla Andalusia and the new agreement?",
                    "score": 0.6018,
                    "answers": "the team of President Juan Manuel Moreno Bonilla Andalusia|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The first clause PP an extension of the agreement signed two years ago that guarantees stability until the end of the legislature is precisely the commitment to exhaust the Andalusia , until the elections This new 'stability agreement ' held, at We end of 2022.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the first clause of the agreement that guarantees stability until the end of the legislature?",
                    "answer": "exhaust the Andalusia"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When was the agreement signed?",
                    "score": 0.689,
                    "answers": "This new ' stability agreement ' held , at We end of 2022|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the commitment to exhaust Andalusia until the elections?",
                    "score": 0.6841,
                    "answers": "the end of the legislature|pobj\tprecisely|advmod\tof 2022|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the agreement signed two years ago?",
                    "score": 0.6474,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es|nsubj\tthe agreement signed two years ago that guarantees stability until the end of the legislature|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship agreement between the government and Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.6451,
                    "answers": "signed two years ago|acl\tat We end of 2022|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'In Spain there is the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo instability, not in Andalusia This new 'stability agreement ' the vice president of the Board and regional the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo of Ciudadanos , Juan Marín.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is the Board spokesman?",
                    "answer": "Elias Bendodo of Ciudadanos"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Bendodo and Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.6848,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es said on 17/03/2021 that ' In Spain there is the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo instability , not in Andalusia This new ' stability agreement ' the vice president of the Board and regional the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo of Ciudadanos , Juan Marín|ROOT\ton 17/03/2021|prep\tthat|mark\t'|punct\tIn Spain|prep\tthere|expl\tIn Spain there is the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo instability|ccomp\tthe|det\tthe Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo instability|attr\t,|punct\tElias|compound\tinstability|appos\t,|punct\tnot|neg\tIn Spain there is the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo instability , not in Andalusia|prep\tThis|det\tnew|amod\t'|punct\tstability|compound\tthat ' In Spain there is the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo instability , not in Andalusia This new ' stability agreement ' the vice president of the Board and regional the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo of Ciudadanos , Juan Marín|dobj\t'|punct\tthe|det\tvice|compound\tof the Board|prep\tthe|det\tthe Board|pobj\tand|cc\tregional|amod\tthe|det\tregional the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo of Ciudadanos , Juan Marín|conj\t,|punct\tElias|compound\tElias Bendodo of Ciudadanos|appos\tof Ciudadanos|prep\t,|punct\tJuan|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the vice president of the Board and regional the Board?",
                    "score": 0.6127,
                    "answers": "the vice president of the Board and regional the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo of Ciudadanos , Juan Marín|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The other most important clause is the commitment that neither PP nor Ciudadanos 'shall favour or accept any transfer of public representatives or elected from one party to another of the Government ', i.e. that PP and Ciudadanos shall not admit the escape of leaders of Ciudadanos to PP , as has happened in Murcia , nor vice versa.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the commitment that PP and Ciudadanos shall not admit the escape of leaders of Ciudadanos to PP?",
                    "answer": "PP and Ciudadanos shall not admit the escape of leaders of Ciudadanos to PP"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the clause that neither PP or Ciudadanos must favor or accept transfers of public representatives or elected from one party to another?",
                    "score": 0.8458,
                    "answers": "accept any transfer of public representatives or elected from one party to another of the Government|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the most important clause?",
                    "score": 0.7751,
                    "answers": "that The other most important clause is the commitment that neither PP nor Ciudadanos ' shall favour or accept any transfer of public representatives or elected from one party to another of the Government ' , i.e. that PP and Ciudadanos shall not admit the escape of leaders of Ciudadanos to PP , as has happened in Murcia , nor vice versa|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the other most important clause?",
                    "score": 0.7743,
                    "answers": "The other most important clause|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between PP and Ciudadanos?",
                    "score": 0.7438,
                    "answers": "on 17/03/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tother|amod\tmost|advmod\tthe|det\tthat|mark\tneither|preconj\tnor|cc\t'|punct\tshall|aux\tor|cc\tany|det\tor|cc\tone|nummod\tthe|det\t'|punct\t,|punct\ti.e.|advmod\tthat|mark\tand|cc\tshall|aux\tnot|neg\tthe|det\tof leaders of Ciudadanos|prep\tleaders of Ciudadanos|pobj\tof Ciudadanos|prep\t,|punct\tas|mark\thas|aux\tas has happened in Murcia|advcl\t,|punct\tnor|cc\tvice|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the commitment of the Members of Ciudadanos?",
                    "score": 0.7236,
                    "answers": "public representatives or elected from one party to another of the Government|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Point two of this addendum reads as follows: 'Respect for the autonomy of the two parties that make up the Andalusian Government, with the commitment that there should be no movement between political formations with parliamentary representation'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the point two of the addendum?",
                    "answer": "'Respect for the autonomy of the two parties that make up the Andalusian Government, with the commitment that there should be no movement between political formations with parliamentary representation'"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the autonomy of the two parties that make up the Andalusian Government?",
                    "score": 0.8426,
                    "answers": "the autonomy of the two parties that make up the Andalusian Government|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between political formations with parliamentary representation?",
                    "score": 0.8155,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tof this addendum|prep\tthis|det\tthis addendum|pobj\tas|mark\t:|punct\t'|punct\tthe|det\tthe|det\tthat|nsubj\tup|prt\tthe|det\tAndalusian|compound\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthat|mark\tthere|expl\tshould|aux\tno|det\tpolitical|amod\t'|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This clause against transfuguism implies that the Andalusian PP and President Moreno Bonilla depart from the national strategy of their party, whose general secretary, Teodoro García Egea, has appealed to the public representatives and elected citizens to leave their party and 'return to the PP house'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.eldiario.es say that this clause against transfuguism implies that the Andalusian PP and President Moreno Bonilla depart from the national strategy of their party?",
                    "answer": "17/03/2021"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Teodoro Garcia Egea appeal to the public representatives and elected citizens?",
                    "score": 0.7945,
                    "answers": "from the national strategy of their party , whose general secretary , Teodoro García Egea , has appealed to the public representatives and elected citizens to leave their party and ' return to the PP house '|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was Teodoro Garcia Egea's position on transfuguism?",
                    "score": 0.7822,
                    "answers": "García|compound\tpublic|amod\tto leave their party and ' return to the PP house|xcomp\t' return to the PP house|conj\tto the PP house|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the clause against transfuguism?",
                    "score": 0.7328,
                    "answers": "that This clause against transfuguism implies that the Andalusian PP and President Moreno Bonilla depart from the national strategy of their party , whose general secretary , Teodoro García Egea , has appealed to the public representatives and elected citizens to leave their party and ' return to the PP house '|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the transfuguism clause?",
                    "score": 0.7234,
                    "answers": "This clause against transfuguism|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Teodoro Garcia Garcia Egea's political affiliation?",
                    "score": 0.7151,
                    "answers": "whose general secretary , Teodoro García Egea ,|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The orange formation fit this message as an 'assault ', 'a hostile, gruesome and disrespectful takeover'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the orange formation call the takeover?",
                    "answer": "'assault"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the orange formation takeover?",
                    "score": 0.7829,
                    "answers": "a hostile , gruesome and disrespectful takeover|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the orange formation do to the message?",
                    "score": 0.7752,
                    "answers": "and|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the meaning of the orange formation?",
                    "score": 0.6841,
                    "answers": "that|mark\torange|compound\tthis|det\tan|det\t,|punct\ta|det\thostile , gruesome and disrespectful|amod\t,|punct\tgruesome and disrespectful|conj\tdisrespectful|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the orange formation?",
                    "score": 0.6779,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es|nsubj\tThe|det\tThe orange formation|nsubj\t'|punct\t'|punct\t'|punct\t'|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The Andalusian president has understood that Pablo Casado's strategy to swallow Ciudadanos, after the political earthquake in Murcia and Madrid, can destabilize his Executive, the most'solid'center right coalition of all those signed by PP and Cs in Spain, and the first alternative of government in Andalusia, after 37 years of the PSOE in power.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How long has the PSOE been in power?",
                    "answer": "37 years"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Casado's strategy do to destabilize his executive?",
                    "score": 0.8103,
                    "answers": "that Pablo Casado 's strategy to swallow Ciudadanos , after the political earthquake in Murcia and Madrid , can destabilize his Executive , the most'solid'center right coalition of all those signed by PP and Cs in Spain , and the first alternative of government in Andalusia , after 37 years of the PSOE in power|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the Andalusian president know about Casado's strategy to swallow Ciudadanos?",
                    "score": 0.7737,
                    "answers": "that The Andalusian president has understood that Pablo Casado 's strategy to swallow Ciudadanos , after the political earthquake in Murcia and Madrid , can destabilize his Executive , the most'solid'center right coalition of all those signed by PP and Cs in Spain , and the first alternative of government in Andalusia , after 37 years of the PSOE in power|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the political earthquake in Murcia and Madrid in Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.7646,
                    "answers": "in Andalusia|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who signed the most'solid' center right coalition?",
                    "score": 0.7234,
                    "answers": "by PP and Cs in Spain|agent\tPP and Cs in Spain|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the Andalusian president and the Spanish Prime Minister?",
                    "score": 0.6717,
                    "answers": "after 37 years of the PSOE in power|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'We have spent four decades complaining that the PP did not have other parties with which to agree in Andalusia and now that there is one, that has helped us to break down the socialists, will we charge it? ', insist sources close to Moreno, aware that 'today, Cs and Vox reach an Andalusian electorate that is not yet within the reach of the PP'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.eldiario.es say on 17/03/2021?",
                    "answer": "'We have spent four decades complaining that the PP did not have other parties with which to agree in Andalusia and now that there is one, that has helped us to break down the socialists, will we charge it?"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What has the PP done to break down the socialists?",
                    "score": 0.8182,
                    "answers": "that has helped us to break down the socialists|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the PP think about Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.7891,
                    "answers": "an Andalusian electorate that is not yet within the reach of the PP|dobj\tthat is not yet within the reach of the PP|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many socialists are there in Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.7261,
                    "answers": "that ' We have spent four decades complaining that the PP did not have other parties with which to agree in Andalusia and now that there is one , that has helped us to break down the socialists , will we charge it|ccomp\tnow that there is one , that has helped us to break down the socialists|advmod\tthat there is one , that has helped us to break down the socialists|ccomp\tone , that has helped us to break down the socialists|attr\tus to break down the socialists|ccomp\tthe socialists|dobj\tnow that there is one , that has helped us to break down the socialists , will we charge it|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the political views of Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.7085,
                    "answers": "in Andalusia|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the political power of Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.7084,
                    "answers": "aware that ' today , Cs and Vox reach an Andalusian electorate that is not yet within the reach of the PP '|amod\tthat ' today , Cs and Vox reach an Andalusian electorate that is not yet within the reach of the PP '|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "This new 'stability agreement 'has been presented after the Governing Council by Marin and the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo, the two most visible sides of the coalition.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the new agreement that has been presented after the Governing Council by Marin and the Board spokesman, Elias Bendodo?",
                    "answer": "'stability agreement"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the stability agreement?",
                    "score": 0.7035,
                    "answers": "This new ' stability agreement '|nsubjpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the agreement between Marin and Bendodo?",
                    "score": 0.6705,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the two most visible sides of the coalition?",
                    "score": 0.6145,
                    "answers": "by Marin and the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo , the two most visible sides of the coalition|agent\tMarin and the Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo , the two most visible sides of the coalition|pobj\tthe Board spokesman , Elias Bendodo , the two most visible sides of the coalition|conj\tmost visible|amod\tthe two most visible sides of the coalition|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the government and the business community?",
                    "score": 0.5521,
                    "answers": "on 17/03/2021|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Both have stressed that the legislature pact signed two years ago is '90 per cent fulfilled ', and that the expansion announced on Tuesday comes to 'strengthen 'the commitments and 'ensure the stability of the Andalusian Executive until the elections, which take place at the end of 2022 '.'We have signed that in this legislature, everyone stays where they are.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When will the elections take place?",
                    "answer": "2022"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long will the Andalusian executive stay in office?",
                    "score": 0.6987,
                    "answers": "the elections , which take place at the end of 2022|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the expansion of the Andalusian executive until 2022?",
                    "score": 0.6733,
                    "answers": "that the expansion announced on Tuesday comes to ' strengthen ' the commitments and ' ensure the stability of the Andalusian Executive until the elections , which take place at the end of 2022 '|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the Andalusian executive and the Andalian legislature?",
                    "score": 0.6501,
                    "answers": "this legislature|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Let's finish it where we start, and then we'll see ', Bendodo has summed up, not mentioning at any time the word'transfugal '[in fact, it doesn't appear in the signed document].",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.eldiario.es say on 17/03/2021?",
                    "answer": "Let's finish it where we start, and then we'll see"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Bendodo say about the word \"transfugal\"?",
                    "score": 0.8327,
                    "answers": "Let 's finish it where we start , and then we 'll see|advcl\twe|nsubj\twhere we start|advcl\t,|punct\tand|cc\twe|nsubj\t'|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\tnot|neg\t'|punct\t,|punct\t]|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does Bendodo say in the signed document?",
                    "score": 0.8013,
                    "answers": "the signed document|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the meaning of the word \"transfugal\"?",
                    "score": 0.6954,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es|nsubj\ton 17/03/2021|prep\t's finish it where we start , and then we 'll see|ccomp\tthen we 'll see|conj\tthat Let 's finish it where we start , and then we 'll see ' , Bendodo has summed up , not mentioning at any time the word'transfugal ' [ in fact , it does n't appear in the signed document ]|ccomp\tat any time|prep\tthe word'transfugal|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The spokesman of the Board is the one who has transferred the agreement with Citizens to the secretary general of the PP, and has explained that the PP 'has understood and supports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government, so that there is no interference or external noise '.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the spokesman of the Board explain about the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government?",
                    "answer": "no interference or external noise"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who transferred the agreement with Citizens to the secretary general of the PP?",
                    "score": 0.7209,
                    "answers": "the one who has transferred the agreement with Citizens to the secretary general of the PP , and has explained that the PP ' has understood and supports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise '|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the agreement with the Andalusian Government?",
                    "score": 0.6705,
                    "answers": "the agreement with Citizens|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the PP and Andalusian Government?",
                    "score": 0.6268,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es said on 17/03/2021 that The spokesman of the Board is the one who has transferred the agreement with Citizens to the secretary general of the PP , and has explained that the PP ' has understood and supports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise '|ROOT\ton 17/03/2021|prep\tthat The spokesman of the Board is the one who has transferred the agreement with Citizens to the secretary general of the PP , and has explained that the PP ' has understood and supports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise '|ccomp\twho has transferred the agreement with Citizens to the secretary general of the PP , and has explained that the PP ' has understood and supports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise '|relcl\tto the secretary general of the PP|prep\thas explained that the PP ' has understood and supports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise '|conj\tthat the PP ' has understood and supports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise '|ccomp\tsupports the decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise '|conj\tthe decision to give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise|dobj\tto give greater stability to the Andalusian Government , so that there is no interference or external noise|acl\tto the Andalusian Government|dative\tAndalusian|compound\tno interference or external noise|attr\texternal|amod\texternal noise|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the spokesman of the Board?",
                    "score": 0.5846,
                    "answers": "The spokesman of the Board|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Bendodo has tried to explain that 'it is not incompatible 'the call of García Egea for the public offices of Cs to pass to the PP with the new pact anti-transfuguism of Andalusia.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Bendodo say on 17/03/2021?",
                    "answer": "'it is not incompatible"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Bendodo say about the new pact with Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.8033,
                    "answers": "that Bendodo has tried to explain that ' it the call of García Egea for the public offices of Cs to pass to the PP with the new pact anti - transfuguism of Andalusia is not incompatible '|ccomp\tfor the public offices of Cs to pass to the PP with the new pact anti - transfuguism of Andalusia|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the new pact against transuguism of Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.7018,
                    "answers": "with the new pact anti - transfuguism of Andalusia|prep\tthe new pact anti - transfuguism of Andalusia|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the new pact between García Egea and Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.6959,
                    "answers": "that ' it the call of García Egea for the public offices of Cs to pass to the PP with the new pact anti - transfuguism of Andalusia is not incompatible '|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Gonzales Egea and Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.6608,
                    "answers": "transfuguism|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I agree with the national leadership of the party, the PP is an open door party to enter and leave ', he insisted.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.eldiario.es say about the PP?",
                    "answer": "PP is an open door party to enter and leave"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What party does the PP belong to?",
                    "score": 0.8024,
                    "answers": "of the party|prep\the|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the National leadership of the party agree with?",
                    "score": 0.757,
                    "answers": "that ' I agree with the national leadership of the party , the PP is an open door party to enter and leave ' , he insisted|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of an open door party to enter and leave?",
                    "score": 0.6237,
                    "answers": "an open door party to enter and leave|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the party's policy on entering and leaving?",
                    "score": 0.6202,
                    "answers": "to enter and leave|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the national leadership of the party?",
                    "score": 0.6196,
                    "answers": "with the national leadership of the party|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But the joint appearance of Marin and Bendodo has immediately revealed the different views on the political crisis facing their parties.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What has immediately revealed the different views on the political crisis facing their parties?",
                    "answer": "the joint appearance of Marin and Bendodo"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What political crisis has Marin and Bendodo shared views on?",
                    "score": 0.8475,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es said on 17/03/2021 that But the joint appearance of Marin and Bendodo has immediately revealed the different views on the political crisis facing their parties|ROOT\ton 17/03/2021|prep\tthat But the joint appearance of Marin and Bendodo has immediately revealed the different views on the political crisis facing their parties|ccomp\tpolitical|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the political views of Marin and Bendodo?",
                    "score": 0.7351,
                    "answers": "their parties|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Marin and Bendodo's political views?",
                    "score": 0.7131,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tBut|cc\tthe|det\tjoint|amod\tof Marin and Bendodo|prep\tand|cc\thas|aux\timmediately|advmod\tthe|det\tdifferent|amod\tthe|det\ttheir|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the views of the political crisis facing their parties?",
                    "score": 0.7055,
                    "answers": "the different views on the political crisis facing their parties|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Why this agreement if you have already signed the Anti-Tranfuguism Pact, which affects the same commitment? 'An Anti-Transfuguism Pact was agreed and signed by the two of us, and now there is an agreement between PP and Cs in Andalusia to ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time ', Marín stressed.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the Anti-Transfuguism Pact?",
                    "answer": "to ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the goal of the Anti-Transfuguism Pact?",
                    "answer": "ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the goal of the Anti-Transfuguism Pact?",
                    "answer": "ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who signed the Anti-Tranfuguism Pact?",
                    "score": 0.8698,
                    "answers": "signed by the two of us|conj\tby the two of us|agent\tthe two of us|pobj\tus|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the Anti-Tranfuguism Pact entail?",
                    "score": 0.8241,
                    "answers": "which affects the same commitment|relcl\tthe same commitment|dobj\tof us|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the Anti-Tranfuguism Pact?",
                    "score": 0.7582,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es|nsubj\twww.eldiario.es said on 17/03/2021 that Why this agreement if you have already signed the Anti - Tranfuguism Pact , which affects the same commitment ?|ROOT\ton 17/03/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tWhy|advmod\tthis|det\tthat Why this agreement|ccomp\tif|mark\tyou|nsubj\thave|aux\talready|advmod\tif you have already signed the Anti - Tranfuguism Pact , which affects the same commitment|advcl\tthe|det\tAnti|compound\t-|compound\tthe Anti - Tranfuguism Pact , which affects the same commitment|dobj\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\tthe|det\tsame|amod\t?|punct\t'|punct\tAn|det\tAnti|compound\t-|compound\tTransfuguism|compound\tAn Anti - Transfuguism Pact|nsubjpass\twas|auxpass\tAn Anti - Transfuguism Pact was agreed and signed by the two of us , and now there is an agreement between PP and Cs in Andalusia to ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time|ccomp\tand|cc\tthe|det\t,|punct\tand|cc\tnow|advmod\tthere|expl\tnow there is an agreement between PP and Cs in Andalusia to ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time|conj\tan|det\tan agreement between PP and Cs in Andalusia to ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time|attr\tbetween PP and Cs|prep\tPP and Cs|pobj\tand|cc\tin Andalusia|prep\tto|aux\tto ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time|acl\tthat|mark\tthe|det\tthe rules of the game|nsubjpass\tof the game|prep\tthe|det\tthe game|pobj\tare|auxpass\tthat the rules of the game are respected this time|ccomp\tthis|det\tthis time|npadvmod\t'|punct\t,|punct\t' An Anti - Transfuguism Pact was agreed and signed by the two of us , and now there is an agreement between PP and Cs in Andalusia to ensure that the rules of the game are respected this time ' , Marín stressed|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Tranfuguism?",
                    "score": 0.7006,
                    "answers": "Tranfuguism|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Asked if the PP's national leadership had failed to comply with the Anti-Transfuguism Pact, signed a few months ago in Congress, Bendodo has answered emphatically that no; and Marín has replied that'in Andalusia no, but in Murcia I am clear that yes'.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Bendodo say about the Anti-transfuguism Pact?",
                    "score": 0.7899,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es said on 17/03/2021 that Asked if the PP 's national leadership had failed to comply with the Anti - Transfuguism Pact , signed a few months ago in Congress , Bendodo has answered emphatically that no ; and Marín has replied that'in Andalusia no , but in Murcia I am clear that yes '|ROOT\ton 17/03/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tAsked if the PP 's national leadership had failed to comply with the Anti - Transfuguism Pact , signed a few months ago in Congress|advcl\tif|mark\tthe|det\tthe PP 's|poss\t's|case\tnational|amod\tthe PP 's national leadership|nsubj\thad|aux\tif the PP 's national leadership had failed to comply with the Anti - Transfuguism Pact , signed a few months ago in Congress|ccomp\tto|aux\twith the Anti - Transfuguism Pact , signed a few months ago in Congress|prep\tthe|det\tAnti|compound\t-|compound\tthe Anti - Transfuguism Pact , signed a few months ago in Congress|pobj\t,|punct\tsigned a few months ago in Congress|acl\ta|det\tfew|amod\ta few months|npadvmod\tin Congress|prep\t,|punct\thas|aux\tthat Asked if the PP 's national leadership had failed to comply with the Anti - Transfuguism Pact , signed a few months ago in Congress , Bendodo has answered emphatically that no ; and Marín has replied that'in Andalusia no , but in Murcia I am clear that yes '|ccomp\temphatically|advmod\tthat|mark\tthat no|ccomp\t;|punct\tand|cc\thas|aux\tMarín has replied that'in Andalusia no , but in Murcia I am clear that yes '|conj\tthat'in Andalusia|prep\tthat'in Andalusia no , but in Murcia I am clear that yes '|ccomp\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tin Murcia|prep\tI|nsubj\tin Murcia I am clear that yes '|conj\tclear that yes|acomp\tthat|mark\tthat yes|ccomp\t'|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the Anti-transfuguism Pact?",
                    "score": 0.6867,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es|nsubj\tto comply with the Anti - Transfuguism Pact , signed a few months ago in Congress|xcomp\tTransfuguism|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'For me those three Cs counselors are fugitives ', he has riveted.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.eldiario.es say about the three Cs counselors?",
                    "answer": "fugitives"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who are the three Cs counsels that are fugitives?",
                    "score": 0.7992,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es said on 17/03/2021 that ' For me those three Cs counselors are fugitives ' , he has riveted|ROOT\tFor me those three Cs counselors are fugitives|ccomp\tthat ' For me those three Cs counselors are fugitives ' , he has riveted|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the three Cs counselors that are fugitives?",
                    "score": 0.7649,
                    "answers": "www.eldiario.es|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The other three points of the stability guarantee agreement deepen the Government's commitments that have already been developed: 'Shielding of health, education and social policies '; 'Economic drive and compliance with the road map for economic reactivation, for which priority is given to the implementation of a second Support Plan for the sectors affected by the health and economic crisis, which will be adopted imminently '; 'Deepening democratic regeneration and reform policy, after decades of mismanagement and corruption of socialist governments in Andalusia'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the other three points of the stability guarantee agreement?",
                    "answer": "'Shielding of health, education and social policies"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the health and economic crisis in Andalusia?",
                    "score": 0.8582,
                    "answers": "the sectors affected by the health and economic crisis|pobj\taffected by the health and economic crisis|acl\tthe health and economic crisis|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the second Support Plan for Andalusia's economic reactivation?",
                    "score": 0.8294,
                    "answers": "' Economic drive and compliance with the road map for economic reactivation , for which priority is given to the implementation of a second Support Plan for the sectors affected by the health and economic crisis , which will be adopted imminently ' ; ' Deepening democratic regeneration and reform policy , after decades of mismanagement and corruption of socialist governments in Andalusia '|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the three points of the stability guarantee agreement for the government's commitments that have already been developed?",
                    "score": 0.8231,
                    "answers": "the Government 's|poss\tthat have already been developed|relcl\tof health , education and social policies|prep\thealth , education and social|nmod\teducation and social|conj\thealth , education and social policies|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of economic reactivation?",
                    "score": 0.7179,
                    "answers": "with the road map for economic reactivation|prep\tthe road map for economic reactivation|pobj\tfor economic reactivation|prep\teconomic reactivation|pobj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}